Stop! You mustn't kill him!
停下！你们不能杀了他！
- Be silent.
- Don't you realise he can help us?
- 安静  - 你们没有意识到他可以帮助我们吗？
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks.
博士是 Daleks 的敌人
How can he help us?
他怎么可能帮助我们？
He is our contact with the guerrillas.
He has valuable information.
他是我们与游击队的联系人, 有宝贵的信息
- You have proof of this?
- I know he's working for them.
- 你有证据吗？  - 我知道他在为他们工作
We will force the truth from him
with the mind analysis machine.
我们可以把真相逼出来, 对他使用思维分析器
But look at him!
看看他！
You've practically killed him just
getting a simple admission of identity.
你们几乎把他弄死了, 他也才坦白承认他的身份而已
He'll die before he tells you anything else.
他在告诉你们任何其它事情之前, 就会死掉了
What is your plan?
你的计划是什么？
Let me interrogate him.
让我来审讯他
Why should you be more successful?
你凭什么就能更成功？
Because I understand human psychology.
因为我懂得人类的心理
I shall be able to gain his confidence.
我将能得到他的信任
To put pressure on him through the girl.
通过那个女孩儿来给他施加压力
By the time I have finished with him,
我跟他一结束
I shall be able to crush the guerrilla
organisation entirely!
我就可以游击队整个碾压掉了！
Release him.
放了他
Now, the control centre is here.
好了, 这就是控制中心
As far as we know, they're being held
prisoner in this block here.
就我们所知, 他们把俘虏扣押在这个区域
And how do we get through?
那我们怎么进去？
The disused underground railway of the old city.
旧城废弃的地下铁路
There's an exit right by this wall.
那边墙边有个出口
I know the Doctor would help you if he could.
我知道博士会尽力帮助你
I am trying to help him!
I've already saved his life.
我正在尽力帮他！我已经救了他的命
Yes, for your own purposes.
是的, 为了你自己的目的
Look, if you do not tell me where they operate from,
what their plans are,
听着, 如果你不告诉我他们在哪里运作, 计划是什么
then the Daleks will destroy both of you.
那 Dalek 就是消灭你们两个
I don't doubt it.
我不怀疑
Do you value life so little?
你如此轻视生命吗？
On the contrary, I value it enormously.
恰恰相反, 我非常珍视它
The Daleks will kill us whatever we tell you.
不管我们告诉你什么, Dalek 都会杀了我们
Not if you cooperate with them.
如果你们跟他们合作的话, 就不会
As you cooperate with them?
像你一样跟他们合作？
Do you really think that makes any difference?
你真觉得这有什么不同？
- They can be reasonable!
- Reasonable?
- 他们不是讲理的？  - 讲理？
They tolerate you as long as you're useful to them.
他们容忍你, 是你对他们还有用
I am a senior government official.
我是政府高官
You, sir, you, sir, are a traitor!
你, 先生, 你, 是一名叛徒！
You're a Quisling!
你是卖国贼！
You do not understand!
你并不明白！
We have helped make things better for the others.
我们帮忙让别人过得更好
We have gained concessions. I have saved lives!
我们获得了 Dalek 的妥协, 我拯救了生命！
Wouldn't you have helped more
by organising the fight against them?
如果你组织人跟他们斗, 不是会帮助更多人吗？
No one can fight against the Daleks.
没人能跟 Dalek 斗
That's not what your criminal guerrillas
seem to think, is it?
你那些游击队罪犯可不这么想, 是吧？
A handful of fanatics?
那群疯子？
Most of them have been killed already.
他们的大多数都已经被杀了
I assure you, there is nothing
they can do to change things.
我向你保证, 没有他们可以改变的事情
- Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
- Anat, look out!
- 终结！终结！终结！  - Anat, 小心!
Come! We must reach the control centre, come!
快, 我们必须赶到控制中心, 来！
No! Come! Come!
不, 快, 快！
For the last time, I tell you
I haven't got any information.
最后一次我跟你说, 我没有任何信息
And quite frankly, even if I had,
I wouldn't give it to you!
而且非常坦白地说, 即使我有, 也不会给你！
- Right, stay where you are!  - Guards!
- 好, 待着别动！  - 警卫！
Guards? You have no guards. They're all dead.
警卫？你没有警卫了, 他们都死了
- Are you all right?  - Yes, thank you.
- 你没事吧？  - 是的, 谢谢你
- All the better for seeing you.
- You're coming with us.
- 见到你们太好了  - 你们跟我们走
No harm must come to these two.
Too much depends on them.
保护好他们俩不受伤, 太多事情取决于他们
- As for you, my friend...
- Put that gun down!
- 至于你, 我的朋友...  - 把枪放下！
There's no point in murdering him.
杀了他没有意义
You don't know how much blood
there is on his hands.
你不知道他手上有多少血
Nevertheless, he's not your real enemy.
不管怎样, 他不是你们真正的敌人
He's helped the Daleks. He's worked for them!
他在帮 Dalek, 他为他们工作！
They would always have found someone.
他们总是能找到一个人的
Now, just leave him.
现在, 留下他吧
Right, let's go.
好了, 我们走
- But how do you know this?
- Oh, there are books.
- 但你们怎么知道这个  - 哦, 有书啊
Even during the wars, people found time
to study, to write about it.
就是在战争期间, 人们还是能找到时间研究、记录这事
What to you has not yet happened
is to us history.
对于你们还没有发生的事情, 对于我们已经是历史了
This history of yours,
it talks about Sir Reginald Styles?
你们的这个历史, 它说到了 Reginald Styles 爵士？
Oh, yeah, he pretended to be working for peace,
哦, 是的, 他假装为和平而工作
but really he just wanted power for himself.
但实际上他只是为他自己争取权力
So the conference he called was just a trick?
所以他召集的会议只是一个诡计？
He managed to lure the world leaders to
a remote country house
他设法把各国领导人骗到一个偏远的乡村房子里
and he pretended they needed absolute quiet
if the meeting was to succeed.
然后假装说他们需要绝对的安静, 否则会议没法成功
But then, there was a devastating explosion...
但是接下来, 就发生了一场毁灭性的爆炸...
And Styles was killed with the others.
然后 Styles 就跟其他人一起炸死了
He must have set a bomb and mistimed the charge.
他肯定是安放了一个炸弹, 但把时间设错了
There were accusations, counter-accusations,
然后就出现了指控、反指控
and then the wars began. That was the turning point.
战争就爆发了, 那就成了转折点
But if this true, Sir Reginald Styles
must be completely round the bend!
但如果这是真的, Reginald Styles 爵士一定完全气疯了！
Er, so, you went back into our time
呃, 所以, 你们就回到我们的时间点
to kill Styles before he could carry out his plan?
就为了在 Styles 实施他的计划之前杀死他？
Right. We've been fighting the Daleks for years.
对, 我们跟 Dalek 斗了很多年
But it was hopeless.
但没什么希望
Eventually we must lose,
so we thought, what else can we do?
最终我们必然会输, 于是我们想, 我们还能做什么？
We learnt through one of our spies
我们通过一个间谍了解到
that the Daleks had succeeded
in creating a time machine.
Dalek 成功创造了一种时间机器
We even managed to steal a copy of
the plans, and we built one of our own,
我们甚至设法偷了一份设计图, 自己造了一台
so that we could go back
into history to the exact point
以便我们可以回到历史中的确切时间点
With one action, we could stop them.
只要一次行动, 我们就可以阻止他们
Mankind could have a chance
to take a new direction!
人类就有了一个机会走向新的方向！
But even now, the transfer isn't always stable.
但即使到现在, 时间转移并不总是稳定
People materialised in your time
and then just faded away.
人在你们的时间出现, 然后又慢慢消失
The ghost that Styles saw?
Styles 看到的那个鬼魂？
Somehow, somehow the Daleks
found what we were doing.
不知怎地, Dalek 发现了我们在做什么
And they sent Ogrons back into your time
after us and attacked one of our men.
他们派 Orgon 回到你们的时间追杀我们, 袭击了我们一个人
Well, that must have been the man
that we saw down by the canal tunnel.
哦, 那肯定就是在运河隧道边看见的那个人
You remember, Jo, the one who vanished
from the ambulance?
你还记得吗, Jo, 在救护车上消失的那个人？
Yes, we fixed on the tunnel
是的, 我们锁定了那个隧道
as a place that was stable
in your time and in ours.
那是在你们和我们的时间都稳定的一个地点
We used it as a transfer point.
Well, you know the rest.
我们把它用作了传送点, 喏, 剩下的你们都知道了
Yes, well there's... There's one thing
I don't quite understand and that is
是的, 不过还有...还有一件事情我不太明白, 那就是
why were you so keen to rescue us?
And believe me, we're grateful, but...
你们为什么这么热衷于救我们？相信我, 我很感激, 但是...
Well, you told us yourself,
you're an old enemy of the Daleks.
哦, 你自己跟我们说过, 你是 Dalek 的老敌人
- Yes?
- Then you will help us to beat them.
- 是吗？  - 而且你会帮助我们打败他们
What do you expect me to do?
你们期望我做什么？
Well, you can succeed where we've failed, Doctor.
就是, 在我们失败的地方获得成功, 博士
We want you to go back into your
own time and kill Styles.
我们期望你回到你的时间, 杀了 Styles
You're asking me to commit murder!
你们要求我去实施谋杀？
No! We're asking you to kill one man
and prevent millions more dying.
不！我们是在要求你去杀一人而救千千万万
- That is still murder.
- Isn't it worth it?
- 那还是谋杀  - 这样不值得吗？
- To save the human race from the Daleks?
- Yes, but would it?
- 就能从 Dalek 手中把人类救出来？  - 是的, 但能吗？
We've told you how it happened.
我们告诉你们了, 这一切是怎么开始的
But your history could be wrong, you know.
但你们的历史可能是错的, 你知道吗？
Now, listen, why don't you
send us back to our time?
现在, 听着, 为什么你不把我们送回我们的时间？
We know the future now,
maybe there are other things we can do?
我们现在已经知道了未来, 也许有其它事情我们可以做？
Monia, we're wasting valuable time!
Every minute that goes by...
Monia, 我们在浪费宝贵的时间！每流逝一分钟...
Doctor, will you help us? It's our only hope.
博士, 你会帮助我们吗？这是我们唯一的希望
I still can't believe that Sir Reginald
Styles is a ruthless murderer.
我还是无法相信 Reginald 爵士是一个冷血杀手
Yes, I agree, Jo.
是的, 我同意, Jo
Vain to the point of arrogance,
a trifle obstinate, perhaps,
要说有点虚荣傲慢，在小事上固执，也许有点
but basically a good man.
但基本上还是个好人
So, if it happened, how did it happen?
所以, 如果那事发生了, 是怎么发生的呢？
Any of your people still in our time zone?
你们还有人在我们的时间区域吗？
- No.  - Well, Shura.
- 没有  - 对了，Shura
He left just to send a message and
we never saw nor heard from him again.
他离开我们去送一个信息, 我们就再也没有看到他, 没听到他
We assumed he must be dead.
我们估计他肯定死了
Look, please believe me,
I'm completely with you about the ends.
看, 请相信我, 我在最终目标上跟你们是完全一致的
I only disagree as to the means.
我只是不同意中间的手段
All right. What do you want to know?
好吧, 你想知道什么？
This mission of yours to the 20th century,
what did you take with you?
你们这次到20世纪的任务, 你们都带了什么东西过去？
The usual battle gear, radio, disintegrators...
通常的战斗装备，无线电，分解器...
- Any sabotage equipment?
- Only a few charges of Dalekenium.
- 有什么搞破坏的设备吗  - 只有一小批 Dalekenium
Dalekenium?
It's a highly effective type of explosive.
这是一种非常有效的炸药
We stole the formula from the Daleks.
我们从 Dalek 那里偷来的配方
- Could it destroy a house?
- What are you trying to say, Doctor?
- 它能够摧毁一栋房子吗？  - 你是想说什么，博士？
Well, don't you see? This has happened before!
喏，你没明白吗？这在以前已经发生了！
What has?
什么已经？
You went back to change history,
你们回到过去改变历史
but you didn't change anything,
you became a part of it.
但你们没有改变任何历史，你们变成了它的一部分
What are you talking about?
你是在说些什么？
If Styles didn't cause that explosion,
somebody else did.
如果不是 Styles 引发了那场爆炸，那就是其他人干的
Well, obviously, but who...
嗯，很显然是，但谁...
Shura!
Isn't that exactly what he would have done?
这不正是他会完成的吗？
One last suicidal attempt to carry out his orders?
为了完成任务而进行最后一次自杀性尝试？
It's possible, I suppose.
这是可能的，我觉得
You're trapped in a temporal paradox!
你们陷入了时间悖论了！
Styles didn't cause that explosion
and start the wars,
Styles 并没有导致那场爆炸，也没有引发战争
you did it yourselves!
是你们自己干的！
You have failed the Daleks.
The Doctor has escaped.
你辜负了 Dalek，博士已经逃走了！
He will be recaptured. I swear it!
他会重新被抓住的，我发誓！
He must be found and destroyed.
必须找到他，并消灭他
He will attempt to return to his own time zone.
他会试图回到他自己的时区
If those guerrillas are helping him,
they will use the tunnel
如果游击队在帮他，他们会使用隧道的
and I am setting up an ambush.
而我就设定一次伏击
If you fail us again,
you will pay with your life.
如果你再次失败，你将付出你的生命作为代价
This is your final chance.
这是你最后的机会
I will go and supervise the operations myself.
我将动身，亲自监督此次行动
Is everything ready?
都准备好了吗？
Security forces have covered the whole tunnel.
警卫队已经包围了整个隧道
Don't worry, they won't escape a second time.
别担心，他们不会再次逃走了
So it has ended as I said it would.
所以到头来结局跟我说过的一样
Did I not tell you it was madness
to fight the Daleks?
我不是告诉过你，和 Dalek 斗争是件疯狂的事吗？
Is it madness to want to see a world
free from their rule?
那想见到一个不受他们统治的世界，也是疯狂的吗？
- It can't be done.
- Oh, yes it can.
- 这不可能的  - 噢，是的，可能
And I can do it. Are you going to stop me?
而且我可以做到，你打算阻止我吗？
Go. I will deal with these criminals myself.
走，我自己来对付这些犯罪分子
I said go!
我说了走！
If only I could be sure.
要是我能确定就好了
You spoke of the war,
你说过这场战争
of its years of suffering and starvation.
多年的苦难和饥饿
Well, I can prevent all that
happening, you know.
但是，我能阻止这一切发生，知道吗
You saved my life.
You could have let them kill me.
你救了我的命。你本可以让他们杀了我的
- Go, quickly.  - Thank you.
- 走，快点  - 谢谢你
Jo, come here and stand by me.
Jo, 过来站我旁边
Sergeant! They're here!
中士！他们在这里！
This is Sergeant Benton calling UNIT HQ.
Benton 中士呼叫 UNIT 总部
Look, we've found them.
Will you get a Jeep over here pronto?
看，我们找到他们了，你能找辆吉普车过来吗？
This way, Doctor.
这边，博士
I am sorry. They were too quick for us.
我很抱歉，他们动作比我们快
They escaped in the darkness.
他们在黑暗中逃走了
You are lying. You have betrayed the Daleks.
你在撒谎。你背叛了 Dalek
No! I told you before,
不！我以前跟你们说过
those security guards
are no match for humans.
这些警卫不是人类的对手
You are a traitor to the Daleks.
你是 Dalek 的叛徒
You must be exterminated!
你必须被终结！
Who knows? I may have helped to exterminate you!
谁知道呢？也许我还帮忙终结了你们！
You have proved yourself worthy
to be the new Controller,
你已经证明了自己的价值，可以担任新的主控
but be warned, the Daleks demand total loyalty
from those who serve them.
但记住，服务于 Dalek 的人，我们要求完全的忠诚
Of course.
当然
We must follow them into
the 20th century time zone.
我们必须跟随他们进入20世纪时区
The peace conference must be destroyed.
和平会议必须被破坏
War must break out.
战争必须爆发
The Dalek conquest of the planet Earth
must not be reversed!
Dalek 对地球的征服不能被逆转！
Look, you're supposed to be in charge of security.
看，你应该负责的是保安
Kindly get on with your job
and leave me to get on with mine.
请继续你的工作, 别妨碍我继续干我的工作
Brigadier! Brigadier,
get everybody out of this house at once!
准将！准将！立即把所有人撤出这栋房子！
Where the devil have you been?
见鬼你们这阵子都到哪里去了？
Never mind all that.
Just clear this house immediately!
别管那个了，立即清空房子里的人！
What's the man talking about?
这个人在说些什么？
Do as he says! Look, there isn't much time!
按他说的做！听着，没有多少时间了！
Locate and destroy the peace conference.
找到和平会议成员，消灭
Exterminate!
终结！
Destroy the human resistance!
消灭人类抵抗力量
Eliminate all humans!
消除所有人类！
Exterminate!
终结！
Brigadier, get this man and all the delegates
out of this area immediately.
准将，把所有人所有代表弄出这个区域，立即！
Use force if you have to!
Jo, you stay here.
实在不行就用武力胁迫！Jo，待在这里
- Sir Reginald, please?
- No, I will not permit it!
- Reginald 爵士，请了  - 不，我不会允许的！
Shura!
Get out of here unless you want to die too!
离开这里，除非你也想死！
I must kill Styles to prevent the war!
我必须杀死 Styles，阻止战争爆发！
Shura, listen to me.
Shura，听我说
Styles and all the delegates
are already leaving this house.
Styles 和所有代表已经离开这栋房子了
You detonate that bomb
and you'll be sacrificing yourself for nothing.
你引发这个炸弹，就会白白牺牲自己了
Benton calling UNIT HQ,
Benton 呼叫 UNIT 总部，Benton 呼叫 UNIT 总部
we just can't hold them, sir!
我们抵挡不住他们了，头儿！
Look, Benton, keep them back
as long as you can.
听着，Benton，阻止住他们，你能拖多久就拖多久
Sir Reginald, this house is under attack
by a hostile force.
Reginald 爵士，这栋房子现在正被敌对势力所攻击
You will please consider yourself
under my orders.
fixme
- Brigadier, I warn you...
- Now be quiet, sir!
- 准将，我警告你...  - 现在给我安静，先生！
- Captain Yates?  - Sir.
- Yates 队长  - 头儿
Get Sir Reginald and all the delegates
away from this area at once.
立即把 Reginald 和所有代表带离这个区域
Locate and destroy the peace conference!
找到和平会议成员，消灭！
Doctor! The Daleks, they're coming into the house!
博士！这些 Dalek，他们要进入房子了
- Daleks? You're lying!  - No, she's not.
- Dalek？你在撒谎！  - 不，她没有
They've come back to make sure that
their version of history isn't changed.
他们回来是为了确保他们那个版本的历史没有发生变化
- Is everybody out of the house?
- Yes, everyone but us.
- 所有人都出去了吗？  - 是的，就只有我们了
Get out of here. Let them come in!
Leave them to me!
离开这里。让他们进来！让我来对付他们！
- No, no! You must come with us!
- You don't understand!
- 不，不行！你必须跟我们走！  - 你没弄明白！
That's Dalekenium. It's the only thing
that's effective against the Daleks.
那是 Dalekenium 炸药，唯一能有效对付 Dalek 的东西
Well, couldn't we set a time fuse?
那，我们不能设置一个延时吗？
No, this stuff's too unstable.
There just isn't time.
不，那东西太不稳定，没有足够时间了
This is something that I must do myself.
Now, get out!
这事必须得我自己干了。现在给我出去！
- Very well.  - Out!
- 好吧  - 出去
Greyhound to Trap One,
灰狗呼叫陷阱一号，灰狗呼叫陷阱一号
do you read me? Over. Greyhound to...
你能收到吗？完毕。灰狗呼叫...
Tell your men to fall back.
Let the Daleks into the house.
告诉你的人后撤，让 Dalek 进屋
Doctor, are you sure that...
博士，你确定这样...
It may not make military sense
but it's the only way.
这也许FIXME, 但这是唯一的办法
All right. Brigadier to all units.
好吧，准将呼叫所有小组
Let them pass! I say again, let them pass!
让他们过去！我再说一遍，让他们过去！
Re-group on the main road, out!
在主路上重新集结，完毕！
Exterminate!
终结！
Eliminate all humans. Exterminate!
消除所有人类，终结！
The human delegates are inside the house.
人类代表都在房子里面
Enter and destroy.
进去消灭他们
- Where are the delegates?
- Where is the man Styles?
- 代表们在哪里？  - Styles 这人在哪里？
They must be found and exterminated!
必须找到他们，终结！
Oh, no, not this time.
噢，不，这次不会
This time it's going to be different!
这次会不一样了！
Well, what happened?
啊，发生什么了？
Your conference has been saved, Sir Reginald.
你的会议得救了，Reginald 爵士
Now it's up to you and your friends
to make sure it's a success.
现在该由你和你这些朋友来确保会议的成功了
- You still have a choice.
- Don't worry.
- 你仍然还有选择  - 别担心
We all know what will happen if we fail.
我们都知道，如果我们失败的话会发生什么
So do we.
We've seen it happen, haven't we, Jo?
我们也是。我们已经见过了，是吧，Jo？
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)